Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we're traveling a little bit and we need to book a hotel room.
我是Catherine，今天我们有点旅行计划，需要订一间酒店房间。
That's right.
没错。
So today we're going to learn all the words and phrases that will help you talk to the
所以今天我们要学习所有能帮你和前台
receptionist in order to book a hotel room.
沟通订房的单词和短语。
Let's check out our dialogue.
我们来看看对话吧。
Madison Sweets, how may I help you?
麦迪逊甜心酒店，有什么可以帮您的？
Yes, I am calling from Mexico.
是的，我从墨西哥打来电话。
I will be in town in a few minutes.
我几分钟后就会到城里。
I'm sorry, I'm not available.
抱歉，我没空。
I will be in town next week and would like to know if you have availability?
我下周会到城里，想知道你们有没有空房？
Ok, ma'am.
好的，女士。
Can you tell me the date you expect to check in?
您能告诉我您预计入住的日期吗？
Yes, July ninth.
好的，7月9号。
I will be there for seven nights.
我会住七个晚上。
We have a junior single suite or a superior double suite available for those dates.
那段时间我们有小单间套房或高级双人套房可选。
What's the difference?
有什么区别？
The junior suite is smaller and has one twin bed, while the superior suite has a double
小套房比较小，有一张单人床，而高级套房有一张双人床
bed and minibar.
和迷你吧。
Ok, I would like to reserve the superior suite.
好的，我想预订高级套房。
Is breakfast included?
包含早餐吗？
Yes, a buffet breakfast is served every morning.
是的，每天早上供应自助早餐。
I will need your name and your credit card details in order to complete the reservation.
我需要您的姓名和信用卡信息来完成预订。
Sure.
好的。
My credit card number is...
我的信用卡号是……
All right.
好了。
We're back.
我们回来了。
So now let's take a look at language takeaway.
现在来看看语言要点部分。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
So we've got a lot of great phrases and words today in language takeaway.
今天语言要点里有很多好用的短语和单词。
The first one comes from the beginning of the dialogue.
第一个来自对话开头。
It's availability.
是“availability”（空房情况）。
All right.
好的。
So the woman wanted to know if the hotel has availability.
那位女士想知道酒店有没有空房。
So what does that mean?
那是什么意思？
That means, do you have free rooms?
意思就是，你们有空房间吗？
Do you have any rooms I could rent?
有没有我能租的房间？
So instead of saying, do you have any free rooms or do you have rooms available?
所以不用问“你们有空房间吗”或“有可用的房间吗”，
You can just say, do you have availability?
你可以直接说“你们有空房吗？”
That's right.
没错。
So you're basically asking the person, do you have anything available?
所以你基本上是在问对方，你们有什么可用的吗？
So what's your availability?
你们空房情况如何？
Very good.
很好。
Okay.
好的。
All right.
So we have availability and obviously the receptionist needs to know when we expect
所以我们有“availability”这个词，显然前台需要知道我们预计
to check in.
什么时候入住。
So this is a noun and a verb, but in today's dialogue, it's used as a verb.
这既是名词也是动词，但在今天的对话里，它用作动词。
So it's something we do to check in.
所以这是我们办理入住的动作。
So the person on the phone would like to know what date you expect to check in.
电话那头的人想知道你预计哪天入住。
That means when will you arrive at our hotel?
意思就是你什么时候到我们酒店？
That's right.
没错。
So maybe we will arrive to the city a couple of days before we check into the hotel.
所以我们可能到城里几天后才入住酒店。
So we really specifically want to know when are you going to start sleeping here?
所以我们特别想知道你什么时候开始在这里住？
That's right.
没错。
And the opposite, so when you leave the hotel, is called check out, to check out.
相反，离开酒店时叫“check out”（退房）。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So we want to check in on July 9th and the receptionist tells us that we have available
所以我们想在7月9号入住，前台告诉我们有
a single suite or a double suite.
单间套房或双人套房可选。
All right.
好的。
So these are two different kinds of rooms.
这是两种不同的房间。
Now a suite is different from a room because it actually means that the space you're going
“套房”和普通房间不同，因为它实际上意味着你要用的空间
to use is more than one room, maybe two rooms or three.
不止一个房间，可能是两三个。
That's right.
没错。
So it's a little bit bigger than just a standard room.
所以比标准房间大一点。
It might have a sitting area or a kitchen area.
可能有个休息区或厨房区。
So that's what a suite is.
这就是套房的意思。
Very expensive rooms are suites as well.
非常贵的房间也是套房。
They have a sitting area and a kitchen and maybe even an extra bedroom.
它们有休息区、厨房，甚至可能多一间卧室。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So we have a single suite.
所以我们有一个单间套房。
That means that we have one of these big rooms that is only for one person.
这意味着我们有一间大房间，只供一个人住。
And the double suite means that two or more people can sleep there.
而双人套房意味着两个或更多人可以在那里睡觉。
That's right.
没错。
So single will be one person and double will be two people.
所以单间是一个人住，双间是两个人住。
And we also heard similar words with the beds because sometimes the rooms aren't really
我们还听到了类似关于床的词，因为有时候房间并不
clear about what kind of beds they have.
明确说明他们有什么样的床。
So this person asked, what's the difference between these rooms?
所以这个人问，这些房间有什么区别？
And the hotel employee answered, well, the junior suite has one twin bed.
酒店员工回答，嗯，普通套房有一张单人床。
All right.
好的。
What's a twin bed?
什么是单人床？
So a twin bed is basically a bed that's only for one person.
单人床基本上就是只供一个人睡的床。
Only one person fits in there.
只能睡一个人。
All right.
好的。
So it's a single bed basically.
所以基本上就是一张单人床。
We call it a twin.
我们叫它单人床。
It's a standard size.
这是标准尺寸。
So everywhere you go, a twin is always for one person.
所以无论你去哪里，单人床总是给一个人用的。
That's right.
没错。
All right.
好的。
And if you want to have another person in bed, we have to get a bigger one.
如果你想和另一个人一起睡，就得要一张更大的床。
And what's that bigger bed called?
那张更大的床叫什么？
It's called a double bed.
叫双人床。
A double bed.
双人床。
So again, double.
所以又是“双”字。
Double room, double bed.
双人房，双人床。
So this means that two people can sleep on the one bed.
这意味着两个人可以睡在同一张床上。
That's right.
没错。
So this is important because sometimes you want to book a hotel room and it will be a
这很重要，因为有时候你想订酒店房间，它会是
double suite, but it will have two twin beds.
双人套房，但里面有两张单人床。
All right.
好的。
So it's a double room.
所以是双人房。
So it's for two people, but each person has their own small bed.
所以是给两个人住的，但每个人有自己的小床。
That's right.
没错。
Two twin beds.
两张单人床。
Mm-hmm.
嗯哼。
Okay.
好的。
And lastly, the superior double suite not only had a double bed, but also had a mini
最后，高级双人套房不仅有一张双人床，还有一个小
bar.
酒吧。
A mini bar.
小酒吧。
So you know what a bar is?
你知道什么是酒吧吗？
It's a place you go to get some alcohol or some drinks, but a mini bar is a little bit
那是你去喝酒或饮料的地方，但小酒吧有点
different, right?
不同，对吧？
Mm-hmm.
嗯哼。
It's a little refrigerator or a little area where you will have snacks and drinks that
它是一个小冰箱或一个小区域，里面有零食和饮料，
you can just basically take freely, but obviously you will have to pay afterwards.
你基本上可以随便拿，但显然之后得付钱。
That's right.
没错。
So you can take them when you're staying there, but when you check out, when you leave, you
所以你在住的时候可以拿，但退房时，离开时，你
have to pay for everything you ate or drank.
必须为你吃或喝的所有东西付钱。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So a lot of words there on Language Takeaway today.
今天“语言小课堂”里有很多词。
Let's take a break and listen to the dialogue again.
我们休息一下，再听一遍对话。
Madison Suites, how may I help you?
麦迪逊套房，有什么可以帮您的？
Yes, I am calling from Mexico.
是的，我从墨西哥打电话来。
I will be in town next week and would like to know if you have availability.
我下周会到城里，想知道你们有没有空房。
Okay, ma'am.
好的，女士。
Can you tell me the date you expect to check in?
您能告诉我您预计入住的日期吗？
Yes, July 9th.
好的，7月9号。
I will be there for seven nights.
我会住七个晚上。
We have a junior single suite or a superior double suite available for those dates.
这些日期我们有普通单间套房或高级双人套房可选。
What's the difference?
有什么区别？
The junior suite is smaller and has one twin bed while the superior suite has a double
普通套房比较小，有一张单人床，而高级套房有一张双人
bed and mini bar.
床和小酒吧。
Okay.
好的。
I would like to reserve the superior suite.
我想预订高级套房。
Is breakfast included?
包含早餐吗？
Yes, a buffet breakfast is served every morning.
是的，每天早上提供自助早餐。
I will need your name and your credit card details in order to complete the reservation.
我需要您的姓名和信用卡信息来完成预订。
Sure.
好的。
My credit card number is...
我的信用卡号是……
All right.
好的。
So now it's time for some phrases.
现在是学习一些短语的时候了。
Let's start with Fluency Builder.
我们从“流利度构建”开始。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
The first phrase in Fluency Builder might seem a little bit strange.
“流利度构建”中的第一个短语可能看起来有点奇怪。
It's I will be in town next week.
就是“我下周会到城里”。
I'll be in town.
我会到城里。
In what town?
什么城？
That's right.
没错。
Well, if you say I will be in town, that basically says I will be in this town.
嗯，如果你说“我会在城里”，那基本上就是说我会在这个城镇里。
I will be there.
我会在那里。
I will be here.
我会在这里。
So, I'll be in the town you're in.
所以，我会在你所在的城镇里。
This is interesting.
这挺有意思的。
So, when I'm talking to someone, maybe Marco is in Chicago and I'm in New York.
所以，当我和某人说话时，比如马可可能在芝加哥，而我在纽约。
I call and say, hey, Marco, I'll be in town next week.
我打电话说，嘿，马可，我下周会到城里。
What are you doing?
你在干嘛？
Right.
对。
I'm going to be in Chicago.
我会去芝加哥。
I want to have a drink.
我想喝一杯。
That means I'm going to be where?
那意味着我会去哪里？
You're going to be in Chicago.
你会去芝加哥。
That's right.
没错。
I'll be in Chicago like Marco is.
我会像马可一样在芝加哥。
I'm not going to talk about where I am now.
我不会谈论我现在在哪里。
This usually means I'm going somewhere else.
这通常意味着我要去别的地方。
That's right.
没错。
So, actually, you can tell your friends that you're going to be in town or sometimes you
所以，实际上，你可以告诉你的朋友你会到城里，或者有时候你
have to tell someone you're going to be out of town.
得告诉别人你要出城。
I'll be out of town.
我要出城了。
That means I won't be where I am now.
意思是我不会待在现在的地方。
I won't be in New York.
我不会在纽约。
I'll be somewhere else.
我会去别的地方。
I'll be in Chicago.
我会在芝加哥。
That's right.
没错。
All right.
好的。
So, we had one where when we were talking specifically about the hotel and maybe what
所以，我们之前有一个场景，当时我们专门讨论酒店以及可能
is included with our suite, we asked a very important question.
包含在套房里的东西，我们问了一个非常重要的问题。
Is breakfast included?
早餐包含在内吗？
Included in what?
包含在什么里面？
In the price.
包含在价格里。
All right.
好的。
So, this is a very common question like you're saying, Marco, but it's not obvious.
所以，这是一个很常见的问题，就像你说的，马可，但并不是显而易见的。
So when you ask, is breakfast included?
所以当你问“早餐包含在内吗？”
That means do I have to pay extra for breakfast?
意思是我需要额外付早餐费吗？
If breakfast is included, I don't have to pay.
如果早餐包含在内，我就不用付钱。
If it's not included, that means I have to pay extra for breakfast.
如果不包含，那就意味着我需要额外付早餐费。
That's right.
没错。
And in this case, breakfast is included, but not just any breakfast.
在这个情况下，早餐是包含的，但并不是随便什么早餐。
It's a buffet breakfast.
这是自助早餐。
My favorite kind of breakfast.
我最喜欢的那种早餐。
So, this is pretty common with hotels.
所以，这在酒店里很常见。
They will serve a buffet breakfast from 7 a.m. to 9 a.m. or whatever.
他们通常从早上7点到9点供应自助早餐，或者类似的时间。
A buffet means that there's a room with tables and food on the tables.
自助餐意味着有一个房间，里面有桌子和食物放在桌子上。
Right.
对。
So, you don't order food.
所以，你不用点餐。
You just take whatever you want.
你直接拿你想吃的东西就行。
That's right.
没错。
So, you can take whatever you want and usually as much as you want.
所以，你可以拿任何你想吃的东西，通常想吃多少拿多少。
That's the best part.
那是最棒的部分。
Okay.
好的。
So, now we know that breakfast is included.
所以，现在我们知道了早餐是包含在内的。
We know what a room is like.
我们知道了房间是什么样的。
So, we're going to make the reservation and the hotel employee says that he needs our
所以，我们要进行预订，酒店员工说需要我们的
credit card details to complete the reservation.
信用卡信息来完成预订。
Credit card details.
信用卡信息。
Now, you might be wondering what details.
现在，你可能想知道具体是什么信息。
Credit card details means the specific information on your credit card.
信用卡信息指的是你信用卡上的具体信息。
All right.
好的。
So, it's pretty common when you're making a purchase on the phone or on the internet.
所以，当你在电话或网上购物时，这种情况很常见。
You have to enter.
你必须输入。
You have to provide your credit card details.
你必须提供你的信用卡信息。
Right.
对。
That means your name, your credit card number, and the expiration date which is when the
这意味着你的姓名、信用卡号以及有效期，也就是
card will no longer be useful.
卡片不再有效的时间。
So, it's necessary because obviously you can say, yeah, I'm going to be there tomorrow
所以，这是必要的，因为显然你可以说，是的，我明天会到，
and then you don't show up and the hotel loses money.
然后你没出现，酒店就会损失钱。
So, they need to make sure that they have you somehow.
所以，他们需要确保以某种方式锁定你。
Yeah.
是的。
That's their way of protecting themselves.
那是他们保护自己的方式。
They want to give you the room but they also don't want to lose money.
他们想给你房间，但也不想亏钱。
Okay.
好的。
So, let's listen to our dialogue one last time and we'll be back to talk a little bit
那么，让我们最后听一遍对话，然后回来再聊一点
more.
更多内容。
Madison Sweets, how may I help you?
麦迪逊甜品店，有什么可以帮您的？
Yes, I am calling from Mexico.
是的，我从墨西哥打电话来。
I will be in town next week and would like to know if you have availability.
我下周会到城里，想知道你们是否有空房。
Okay, ma'am.
好的，女士。
Can you tell me the date you expect to check in?
您能告诉我您预计入住的日期吗？
Yes, July 9th.
是的，7月9日。
I will be there for seven nights.
我会在那里住七个晚上。
We have a reservation.
我们有预订。
I'm going to be there for seven nights.
我打算在那里住七个晚上。
Okay.
好的。
I'm going to be there for seven nights.
我打算在那里住七个晚上。
Okay.
好的。
I'm going to be there for seven nights.
我打算在那里住七个晚上。
Okay.
好的。
I'm going to be there for seven nights.
我打算在那里住七个晚上。
Okay.
好的。
I'm going to be there for seven nights.
我打算在那里住七个晚上。
Okay.
好的。
All right.
行。
So, talking about hotels, I think one of the most important things out of this, well, not
所以，说到酒店，我觉得其中最重要的一点，嗯，不是
important but also something that you should know is that the minibar is always so expensive.
重要，而是你应该知道的是，迷你吧总是很贵。
It is expensive.
确实很贵。
Be very careful when you're going into that minibar.
用迷你吧的时候要非常小心。
Sometimes it seems like a really good idea.
有时候它看起来是个好主意。
You're hungry and there are crackers or you want a beer.
你饿了，里面有饼干，或者你想喝杯啤酒。
But you have to look at the menu because the menu will have the prices and maybe something
但你必须看菜单，因为菜单上会有价格，也许外面商店里很便宜的东西
that's really cheap in a store outside is really expensive at a hotel.
在酒店里却很贵。
And I think sometimes, I don't know, sometimes it's even hard to find that little menu so
而且我觉得有时候，我不知道，有时候甚至很难找到那个小菜单，
you don't even know what the prices are.
所以你根本不知道价格是多少。
But you're so thirsty, you just want to have something to drink now and it ends up costing
但你太渴了，只想马上喝点什么，结果最后花了
you $10.
你10美元。
So, be careful.
所以，要小心。
Anytime you're in a hotel room, expect the prices to be pretty high for the things in
任何时候你在酒店房间里，都要预料到酒店里的东西价格会很高。
the hotel.
Unless, of course, there's a sign or a piece of paper that says that something is free
当然，除非有牌子或纸条写着某样东西是免费的
or complimentary.
或赠送的。
Yeah, that's right.
是的，没错。
Complimentary water is very common in hotels.
赠送的水在酒店里很常见。
They'll give you two free bottles of water.
他们会给你两瓶免费的水。
That's right.
没错。
So, complimentary means you don't have to pay for it.
所以，赠送的意思就是你不用付钱。
But if there's no sign, then expect to pay a lot.
但如果没有牌子，那就准备好付高价吧。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So, if you guys have any questions or any doubts or you want to suggest any other lesson
所以，如果你们有任何问题或疑问，或者想建议其他课程
topic, you can visit us at EnglishPod.com.
主题，可以访问我们的网站EnglishPod.com。
We'll hope to see you there.
我们希望能在那里见到你。
Until next time.
下次再见。
Bye.
再见。
Ladas, 있을leri teener, tulips and skunk.
拉达斯，有东西，郁金香和臭鼬。